<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HeyRecipe</string>
    <string-array name="favorite_websites">
        <item>Sinigang na Baboy</item>
        <item>Tinolang Manok</item>
        <item>Kare Kare</item>
        <item>Adobo</item>
        <item>Beef Caldereta</item>
        <item>Dinuguan</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="descriptions">
        <item>Filipino pork soup with taro cooked in a sour broth. Sinigang is my comfort food, and one of the first few dishes that I tried to make way back when I was starting to learn how to cook.</item>
        <item>Tinolang Manok is a great tasting and healthy dish to prepare for your family. It is easy to cook and friendly on the budget.</item>
        <item>Kare Kare is a traditional Filipino stew complimented with a thick savory peanut sauce. The commonly used meats for this dish are ox tail, tripe, and pork leg; on some occasions goat and chicken meat are also used.</item>
        <item>It is a dish composed of pork slices cooked in soy sauce, vinegar, and garlic. There are version wherein onions are also added. Adobo is a popular dish in the Philippines, along with Sinigang.</item>
        <item>Another favorite Filipino dish is the Kaldereta. It is a hearty meat dish using chevon (goat meat), beef, or pork combined with potatoes, carrots, tomato sauce, and liver spread or liver paste. </item>
        <item>Pork Dinuguan is a type of stew native to the Philippines. It is peculiar when compared to other types of stews because of the use of pork blood as the main ingredient. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="recipes">
        <item>Time:1 hr 15 mins Servings: 4 \n\n
            Ingredients: \n
            1 tablespoon vegetable oil \n
            1 small onion, chopped \n
            1 teaspoon salt \n
            1 (1/2 inch) piece fresh ginger, chopped \n
            2 plum tomatoes, cut into 1/2-inch dice \n
            1 pound bone-in pork chops \n
            4 cups water, more if needed \n
            1 (1.41 ounce) package tamarind soup base (such as Knorr®) \n
            ½ pound fresh green beans, trimmed \n\n
            Steps: \n
            1. Heat vegetable oil in a skillet over medium heat. Add onion; cook and stir until softened and translucent, about 5 minutes. Season with salt. \n
            2. Stir in ginger, tomatoes, and pork chops. Cover and reduce heat to medium-low. Turn the pork occasionally, until browned. \n
            3. Pour in water and tamarind soup base. Bring to a boil, then reduce heat and simmer until the pork is tender and cooked through, about 30 minutes. \n
            4. Stir in green beans and cook until tender.</item>
        <item>Time:50 mins Servings: 4 \n\n
            Ingredients: \n
            1 tablespoon cooking oil \n
            1 medium onion, chopped \n
            2 cloves garlic, minced \n
            1 (1 1/2 inch) piece fresh ginger, peeled and thinly sliced \n
            1 tablespoon fish sauce \n
            3 pounds chicken legs and thighs, rinsed and patted dry \n
            2 (14 ounce) cans chicken broth \n
            1 chayote squash, peeled and cut into bite-sized pieces \n
            salt and ground black pepper to taste \n
            1 head bok choy, chopped \n
            1 (8 ounce) package fresh spinach, chopped \n\n
            Steps: \n
            1. Gather all ingredients. \n
            2. Heat oil in a large pot over medium heat. Add onion and garlic; cook and stir until fragrant, about 2 minutes. \n
            3. Add ginger and fish sauce; cook and stir for 1 to 2 minutes. Stir in chicken and cook for 5 minutes. \n
            4. Pour in chicken broth and cook for 5 minutes. Add squash and simmer until chicken is no longer pink in the center, about 10 minutes. Season with salt and pepper. \n
            5. Add bok choy and spinach; cook until spinach is just wilted, 1 to 2 minutes. Serve hot.</item>
        <item>Time:2 hrs 35 mins Servings: 6 \n\n
            Ingredients: \n
            4 ½ pounds beef oxtails \n
            3 cups water, or more as needed \n
            2 beef bouillon cubes \n
            ½ pound bok choy, chopped \n
            ½ pound long beans, cut into bite-sized pieces \n
            ½ pound eggplant, cubed \n
            2 tablespoons olive oil \n
            1 medium onion, chopped \n
            2 cloves garlic, minced \n
            1 teaspoon achiote powder \n
            3 tablespoons smooth peanut butter \n\n
            Steps: \n
            1. Bring oxtails and water to a boil in a large pot. Reduce the heat to medium-low and simmer until tender, at least 2 hours, adding more water as necessary. Skim as much fat from the top of the liquid as possible.\n
            2. Transfer oxtails to a plate. Crumble beef bouillon cubes into the pot and stir to dissolve. Add bok choy, beans, and eggplant and simmer until tender, 10 to 15 minutes.\n
            3. While the vegetables are simmering, heat olive oil in a large pot over medium heat. Add onion and garlic; cook and stir until tender, about 5 minutes. Stir in achiote powder. Stir in peanut butter until melted.
            Add about 1/2 of the simmering broth and simmer for 5 minutes. Add oxtails and cook for 5 minutes. Transfer remaining broth and vegetables to the pot and stir to combine. Serve hot. \n</item>
        <item>Time:2 hrs 30 mins Servings: 6 \n\n
            Ingredients: \n
            ½ pound pork belly, cut into 1 1/2-inch cubes \n
            ½ pound pork loin, cut into 1 1/2-inch cubes \n
            2 tablespoons groundnut oil, divided \n
            4 cloves garlic, diced \n
            1 (2 inch) piece fresh ginger, chopped  \n
            1 red chile pepper, chopped, or more to taste  \n
            12 whole black peppercorns \n
            2 teaspoons brown sugar \n
            3 bay leaves, or more to taste \n
            1 pinch cumin seeds, or to taste \n
            ½ apple, diced \n
            1 tablespoon apple cider vinegar \n
            1 tablespoon dark soy sauce \n
            2 tablespoons unsalted butter, divided \n
            1 pinch salt and ground black pepper to taste \n
            1 medium red onion, roughly chopped \n
            1 green bell pepper, diced \n
            1 (3.5 ounce) package shiitake mushrooms, roughly chopped \n
            1 cup sparkling lemonade \n
            2 teaspoons cornstarch \n
            1 cube chicken bouillon \n\n
            Steps: \n
            1. Combine pork belly and pork loin in a large bowl. Toss with 1 tablespoon groundnut oil to coat. Add garlic, ginger, red chile, peppercorns, brown sugar, bay leaves, and cumin. Mix in diced apple, cider vinegar, and soy sauce. Stir to coat the pork. Marinate in the fridge, stirring occasionally, for at least 1 hour. \n
            2. Heat remaining 1 tablespoon oil in a deep pan over medium heat. Melt 1 tablespoon butter in the pan and sprinkle in salt and pepper. Add onion, bell pepper, and mushrooms. Fry until softened, about 5 minutes. Add the pork and marinade; cook until pork starts to brown, about 6 minutes. Stir in lemonade, cornstarch, and bouillon; sauce should cover the pork and vegetables.\n
            3. Reduce heat and simmer, covered, until liquid is reduced and pork is tender but still slightly pink in the center, about 1 hour. An instant-read thermometer inserted into the center should read at least 145 degrees F (63 degrees C). Add the remaining 1 tablespoon butter 10 minutes before pork is finished cooking. Discard bay leaves before serving.\n</item>
        <item>Time:1 hr 30 mins Servings: 6 \n\n
            Ingredients: \n
            2 pounds beef chuck, cubed \n
            12 ounces chorizo sausage \n
            ¼ cup garlic, minced \n
            ¼ cup white vinegar \n
            ¼ cup soy sauce \n
            2 tablespoons olive oil, or as needed \n
            1 onion, chopped \n
            1 green bell pepper, chopped \n
            3 cups tomato sauce \n
            2 cups peeled and cubed potatoes \n
            1 cup drained canned peas \n
            1 teaspoon salt \n
            1 teaspoon ground black pepper \n\n
            Steps: \n
            1. Combine beef, chorizo, garlic, vinegar, and soy sauce in a skillet over medium heat; cook and stir until beef is browned and liquid is reduced, about 20 minutes. Remove from heat.\n
            2. Meanwhile, heat olive oil in a pot over medium heat; cook and stir onion and bell pepper in hot oil until onion is translucent, 5 to 10 minutes. Add tomato sauce and simmer until liquid is slightly reduced, 3 to 5 minutes.\n
            3. Stir beef-chorizo mixture into tomato sauce mixture; bring to a boil. Reduce the heat to medium-low, cover the pot, and simmer for 30 to 40 minutes \n
            4. Stir potatoes, peas, salt, and pepper into stew; simmer until beef is tender and potatoes are cooked through, 20 to 30 minutes. Add water if needed.</item>
        <item>Time:1 hr 15 mins Servings: 4 \n\n
            Ingredients: \n
            2 lbs. pork shoulder cubed \n
            1 1/4 cups pork blood \n
            1 piece Knorr Pork Cube \n
            4 pieces long peppers \n
            2 pieces onion chopped \n
            6 cloves garlic minced \n
            2 cups water \n
            ¾ cup white vinegar \n
            3 pieces dried bay leaves \n
            3 tablespoons cooking oil \n
            1 tablespoon granulated white sugar \n
            Salt and ground black pepper to taste \n
            Steps: \n
            1. Saute onion for 30 seconds. Add garlic. Continue to cook until onion softens. \n
            2. Add pork. Saute for 3 to 5 minutes. \n
            3. Pour water. Let boil. Add bay leaves and vinegar. Let the liquid re-boil. \n
            4. Add Knorr Pork Cube. Stir. Cover and simmer for 1 hour. Note: add water as needed.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>